Finding Aid for Daughters of the American Revolution. Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1896-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Daughters of the American Revolution. Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1896-2009
Daughters of the American Revolution. Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
3 oversize volumes
2 oversize folders
10 linear feet
851069 Be.1 2; Be.1 Outsize
Ann Arbor chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution; minutes and other organizational records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records have been deposited by the chapter (donor no. 1066 ) in many accessions beginning in 1940.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution was founded in Ann Arbor, Michigan in 1896. The chapter was named in honor of the wife of University of Michigan President James B. Angell.
The record group has been arranged into the following series: Minutes; Published Material; Yearly Files; Officers Files; Membership records; Topical Files; Genealogical records; Scrapbooks, Historians Albums; and Visual Materials. Of interest are files relating in part to the chapter's activities during the Spanish-American War and World War I. The genealogical records include cemetery records for various Washtenaw County cemeteries.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Cemeteries--Michigan.; Daughters of the American Revolution. Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Patriotic societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Washtenaw County (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; World War, 1914-1918.; Spanish-American War, 1898.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Knitting.; Sewing.; Theatrical productions.; Women--Organizations.; World War, 1914-1918.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Videotapes.
- Minutes
  (in volumes except where indicated)
  - 1896-1903 (Box 1)
  - 1903-1910 (Box 1)
  - 1910-1913 (Box 1)
  - 1914-1920 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1928 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1946 (Box 1)
  - 1946-1951 (Box 1)
  - October 1952-May 1955 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1959, 1 folders (Box 1)
  - 1960-1965 (regular meetings), 1 folders (Box 1)
  - 1960-1965 (board meetings), 1 folders (Box 1)
  - 1965-1971 (board meetings), 1 folders (Box 2)
  - 1967-1971 (regular meetings), 1 folders (Box 2)
  - 1971-1972 (mixed records), 1 folders (Box 2)
  - 1972-1973 (mixed records), 1 folders (Box 2)
  - 1973-1974 (mixed records), 1 folders (Box 2)
  - 1975 (mixed records), 1 folders (Box 2)
  - 1976-1987, 9 volumes booklets (Box 2)
  - 1987-1991 (mixed records), 1 folders (Box 2)
  - 1996-2009 (Box 10)
    (chapter and board meetings)
- Published
  - Bylaws and programs from banquets (Box 2)
  - Yearbooks/membership books 1899-2007 (scattered dates), 2 folders (Box 2)
- Yearly Files (mainly reports)
  - 1896 (application for charter) (Box 3)
    (see also charter, July 3, 1896 in oversize folder)
  - 1899-1944, 36 folders (Box 3)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - 1973-1975 (Box 3)
  - 1988-1991 (Box 3)
  - 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - Undated (Box 3)
- Officers Files
  (officers yearly reports filed in Yearly Files series)
  - Regent's papers 1917-1921, 1973-1975, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Treasurer's papers 1947-1953, 1968-1971, 1974-1974, 1988-1991, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Historian's papers 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Membership records
  - Membership book 1902-1913 (Box 4)
  - Membership book 1896-1909 (Box 4)
  - Membership book 1896-1911 (Box 4)
  - Membership book circa 1926-1948 (Box 4)
  - Membership book circa 1896-1925 (Box 4)
  - Membership applications to the National Society of the DAR
    (include genealogical information about individual applicants)
    - A-L (Box 4)
    - M-Z (Box 9)
  - Membership printout 1972, 1990s, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Past membership records (transfers) (Box 9)
  - Registrar's annual reports (Box 9)
- Topical files
  - Anniversary celebrations 1921, 1926, 1946, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Boulder lawsuit 1991-1994 (Box 9)
    (traffic death caused when car hits commemorative boulder)
  - Chaplain's file 1989-1994 (Box 9)
  - Essays, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Memorials to members (Box 9)
    (see also resolutions, January 14, 1904 passed on death of Mrs. Angell in oversize folder)
  - Reports of activities at the DAR national congresses 1898-1939 (scattered dates) (Box 5)
  - Reports to the State Regent of the DAR 1896-1971 (scattered dates) (Box 5)
  - Revolutionary War soldiers (graves of) in Washtenaw County and related (Box 5)
  - Roster of officers 1896/1897-2007/2008 (Box 5)
  - Sarah Caswell Angell loan fund (Box 5)
  - Spanish-American War activities (Box 5)
  - State directories (Box 5)
  - Veteran-Patient award 1992-1994 (Box 5)
  - Women in American History 2004 (Box 5)
  - World War I activities, including letters from men in service (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Genealogical records
  - Cemetery records
    - Base Line Cemetery, Unadilla (Box 5)
    - Bethlehem Cemetery, Scio Township (Box 5)
    - Dixboro Cemetery, Superior Township (Box 5)
    - Four-Mile Lake Cemetery (Box 5)
    - Hudson Cemetery (Box 5)
    - Lapham Cemetery (Box 5)
    - Leland Cemetery, Northfield, Michigan (Box 5)
    - Mt. Calvary, Sylvan Township (Box 5)
    - Oak Grove Cemetery, Chelsea, Michigan (Box 5)
    - Oak Grove Cemetery, Manchester, Michigan (Box 5)
    - Pray Cemetery, Superior Township (Box 5)
    - Reynold's Corners Cemetery (Box 5)
    - Sylvan Cemetery (Box 5)
    - Town Hall Cemetery (Box 5)
    - Vermont Cemetery (Box 5)
    - Washtenaw County cemeteries (various), 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Index to obituaries of people 90 and over in Ann Arbor News and Detroit News, 1987-1990 (Box 5)
  - Birth and marriage records (Box 5)
  - Family records, 3 folders (Box 5)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1902-1910 (Box 6)
  - 1910-1937 (Box 6)
  - 1932-1937 (Box 6)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - 1938-1940 (Box 6)
  - Loose clippings 1928-1929, undated, 3 folders (Box 6)
- Historians Albums
  (mainly clippings with some photos and programs)
  - 1913-1915 (Box 6)
  - 1939-1940 (some 1948-1949) (Box 7)
  - 1955-1960 (Box 7)
  - 1956-1959 (Box 7)
  - 1960-1965 (Box 7)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - 1965-1969 (Box 7)
  - 1965-1971 (Box 7)
  - 1967-1969 (Box 7)
  - 1971-1975 (Box 8)
  - 1976-1978 (Box 8)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - 1979-1981 (Box 8)
  - 1975-1991 1984-1991 (Volume 1)
  - 1991-1993 (Volume 2)
  - 1993-1995 (Volume 3)
- Visual materials
  - Photographs; includes scenes from patriotic play presented during World War I, photo of women knitting and sewing as part of war effort, photo of the George Washington Club, 1911 (Box 8)
  - Videotape (VHS), 1991 Outstanding History Teacher Program (Box 8)